Hello and welcome
大家好 欢迎来到
to the production metaverse.
制片元宇宙
Today, we're gonna walk through,
今天 我们将探讨
what is the production metaverse?
什么是制片元宇宙
How is metadata used to orchestrate the pipeline
元数据是如何用于协调工作室
of a studio and a production?
和制片流程
What are some of the unique challenges?
有哪些独特的挑战
And how is it used in a virtual production
它又是如何在这些工作室的
across these studios? 10-p
虚拟制作中使用的 10-p
Just to start off with some of the foundation
先说说制作过程的
of what a production process looks like,
一些基础知识
it really starts with a script, the foundation of the story.
脚本是起点 那是故事的基石
From there you build out research,
在此基础上调研
where you're pulling images from the web,
你从网络上调取图片
you're building unique pieces of content
你用故事板和概念图
with storyboards and concept art,
创造独特的内容
you're doing scouting and location photos
你跑遍世界各地
from around the world,
拍摄照片
set design with architectural drawings,
用架构图纸进行布景设计
casting with a whole range of other content. 21-p
用一系列其他内容进行浇筑成型 21-p
Then as you go into shooting, you're gonna be capturing
然后当你进入拍摄阶段时 你会以高帧率
all sorts of different resolutions at high frame rates,
捕捉各种不同的分辨率
and potentially multiple cameras
并可能在多个地点的
across multiple units in multiple locations.
多个单位拍摄多个镜头
It's not uncommon for a production to generate
一个制片流程在短短的几个月内
hundreds of terabytes, if not petabytes,
就可能积累上千TB甚至PB的素材
in a number of months,
这种情况并不罕见
and require that all of that content be uploaded
而且还需要将所有这些内容上传到云端
into the cloud, distributed out to multiple vendors,
分发给多个制作团队
all working on that content in different ways
他们都以不同的方式
and at different phases,
在不同的阶段处理这些内容
and different needs for the production process. 33-p
并且在制作过程中有不同的需求 33-p
Editorial will then cut that all together
剪辑部门将把这些东西剪在一起
and connect all those VFX vendors and all those VFX layers
并将所有视觉特效团队和视觉特效层
and elements that come together,
还有视觉元素组合在一起
and all the while feeding the marketing machine
同时将市场营销
and the licensing machine up into the studio. 38-p
和许可授权机制引入工作室 38-p
As I said, the foundation really starts with the script.
如我所说 故事的基础其实从脚本开始
And what's interesting is a script is a structured document,
有意思的是 脚本是一个结构化的文件
you have scenes on the left, exterior, interior,
左边有场景 室外 室内
day/night labels, story locations, characters, et cetera,
白天/夜晚标签 故事地点 人物等等
all consistently structured in this document. 43-p
所有这些在脚本中一直都有 43-p
Taking that foundation as we expand out
以此为基础 我们从故事地点
from the story location into, say,
扩展到实际地点
the physical location of where is that set going to be a shot,
比如实际拍摄的片场
or are they going to create it in a particular stage?
或者是用于拍摄的特定布景
You also have virtual elements with sequences and shots,
其中也有虚拟元素的序列和镜头
so how's the visual effects department going to break down
那么视觉效果部门要如何分解信息呢
the information, and how does this all connect together
这一切和制片元宇宙
into this actual production metaverse? 51-p
又是如何关联的呢 51-p
Even going deeper into VFX,
再细说视觉特效
if you take, say, a particular shot,
以某个特定镜头为例
it's broken up into hundreds, if not thousands, of frames,
它会被分解成至少数百帧画面
and there's layers to those frames,
这些帧有不同的层
maybe a foreground plate or a background plate.
也许是前景板或背景板
That foreground plate could be made up of models
前景板可能是由模型
and rigs and textures,
骨架和贴图组成的
and combined with footage to come together
并与连续镜头结合在一起
just to create a couple of seconds of a beautiful image. 60-p
只是为了创造出几秒钟的优美画面 60-p
And as an example,
例如
we could use maybe a foreground plate of a guy on a horse.
我们可以用一个骑马的人作为前景板
Whack in a background layer, some smoke and some people
在背景层中加入一些烟雾 人群
and fire, I'll light it, color it,
还有硝烟 提亮 上色
and you get this beautiful image.
你就会得到这张美妙的图片
So if you can think of that happening thousands,
因此你可以想象一下在全球范围内
if not tens of thousands of times across all of these
数以千计的镜头
millions of frames, thousands of shots and
数以千万计的帧
distributed globally to create this one piece of content
都经过这样的处理 就是为了制作这一件作品
and surrounding articles. 70-p
以及周边产品 70-p
So what's important is you get a consistent framework of how
因此 重要的是你需要有一个统一的框架
to structure that information from the file metadata,
如何从文件元数据构建这些信息
to how the files are structured within assets,
文件在资源中结构如何
the connective tissue of how a character is connected
角色与演员之间的连接组织
to an actor, leveraging AI analysis for automation of that
尽可能利用人工智能分析
as much as possible,
实现自动化
connecting a shot to a vendor through external databases
通过诸如FileMaker Ftrack或Shotgun等外部数据库
like File Maker, Ftrack or a Shotgun database. 78-p
将镜头与视效团队联系起来 78-p
How you pull in the pillars from all different phases
如何从制片的所有不同阶段建立支柱
of production from casting and pre-production
从选角和前期制作
to camera on set, to the editorial of post and the archive,
到现场拍摄 到后期的编辑和归档
all the way into the metaverse and into entities. 82-p
一直到元宇宙和实体 82-p
So we leverage all this data to orchestrate the pipeline
于是我们利用所有这些数据来协调状态变化
of status changes and triggering events for transcodes
和触发事件的流程 以便在不同的情况下
and file transfers with different applications
用不同的应用程序进行转码和文件传输
in different events, all in the need of moving this data
这都是为了尽可能快地移动这些数据
as fast as possible to give creatives as much time
以便给予创作者尽可能多的时间
to make those decisions before they hit that deadline. 88-p
在他们赶在最后期限之前做出决策 88-p
That's one interesting thing about production
说到制片 不得不提的是
is you've got a release date
你有一个发布日期
and the goal is how can you create
而制片的目标是
the greatest film possible in that amount of time?
在有限的时间内创造出最好的作品
So functionally our role is to help facilitate
因此我们的作用就是
the orchestration, the speed of decisions,
尽可能促进协作 提高决策的速度
and creative flow as much as possible. 95-p
以及源源不断的创意 95-p
And so some of the key challenges that we find through
而我们在浏览器中发现的一些关键挑战
browsers is things like dealing with big file sizes
包括处理大尺寸的文件
and the need for UDP acceleration of large file
以及对全球范围内大文件传输
transfers distributed globally around the world.
进行UDP加速
When you've gotta be uploading
当你必须在一夜之间
many terabytes overnight, and it's required to be delivered
上传数TB的文件 并且需要传到另一个地方
in a location for that next artist
交付给下一个艺术家来处理时
to work on it, you just really need the robustness
你真的需要Aspera和Signiant这样的常用工具
of commonly used tools like (?) and Asignet
来为你提供稳健性
but to be able to get native support in the browser
但是如果能够在浏览器中获得本地支持
would be amazing. 106-p
那就太好了 106-p
Upload folders, uploading folders, of course,
当然 上传文件夹
many challenges there in a browser right now,
现在在浏览器中存在许多挑战
you know, structured files, like a model
结构化的文件 比如一个模型
that has a certain relationship to a rig
有相关联的骨架和贴图
and a texture maintaining those structures,
要保持这些结构
commonly requires people to zip things up
通常需要人们压缩文件
and then have them decompress on upload. 113-p
然后在上传后将它们解压 113-p
Those robust transfers across a long haul, you know,
那些在全球分布的团队中进行的
globally distributed teams where you're shooting
长距离稳健的数据传输
in New Zealand and your post house is in LA
比如在新西兰拍摄 而后期工作室在洛杉矶
and VFX  house is in the UK, et cetera,
视觉特效公司在英国等等
just being able to move data really fast is required,
就需要能够高速传输数据
especially on location, the idea of sort of drop zones
特别是投放点的概念
of how do you find that, a big pipe to get the data
如何找到一个大流量的渠道
to where you need as fast as possible. 121-p
尽可能快地把数据送到你需要的地方 121-p
And we also see a lot of duplication of files.
我们也经常遇到文件重复的问题
You know, if there was the possibility
如果可以在客户端
of a client-side checksum
拿到文件校验值
where you would get a computable, a fingerprint,
也就是一个可计算出来的文件指纹
to realize you've already got that file in your system,
能够识别出你的系统中已经有了这个文件
because we're moving so many files around
因为我们在不同的地方传输了
in different locations,
这么多的文件
just to be able to exchange a common hash,
要是能够交换一个共同的哈希值进行校验
would just allow for a lot faster transfers
这将在没有重复数据的情况下
without duplicate data. 131-p
实现更快的传输 131-p
And editing, of course, the hybrid nature of being
当然 编辑既具有云端也具有实地属性
on prim, on location, in a studio, in the home,
既具有工作室也具有家中属性
orchestrating that data, getting it to where it needs to be
协调传输这些数据 在合理的时间内
in a reasonable amount of time.
把它送到需要的地方
You know, this is also driving the need to bring the desktop
这也推动了将桌面端带到数据
to the data or the desktop in the cloud.
或者说带到云端的需求
So accelerating the needs of common operating system
因此 直接在云中运行通用操作系统
and common applications to run directly in the cloud
和普通应用程序的需求
is accelerating.
正在日益增长
And a lot of challenges dealing with raw media costs,
还有很多处理原始媒体成本的挑战
constantly requiring transcoding,
总是需要转码
very difficult to protect with any form of watermarking. 143-p
难以用任何形式的水印保护 143-p
Now with playback, we've seen a good evolution,
在成品播放方面已经有了良好的发展
obviously on the browsers, as we've seen,
显然在浏览器上 正如我们所看到的
many video technologies accelerate with fragmented MP4s
在诸多视频技术的加持下 如碎片化的MP4
and low-latency streaming live is accelerating across
以及低延迟流媒体直播目前正在加速发展
this industry right now, but the need for higher bit rates,
但对更高比特率的需求
higher fidelity, 5.1 audio, et cetera,
更高的保真度 5.1音频等等
is definitely a higher requirement.
肯定是一个更高的要求
Visual and forensic watermarking have always been
视觉和取证水印一直是
fundamental to what we do. 152-p
我们工作的基础 152-p
We used to be able to have a
在Flash的安全性还凑合的时代
compiled container back in the days when Flash
我们曾经能够编译一个容器
was semi-secure and allowed you to have a DRM
可以让你给媒体流加上数字版权保护
protected stream with a client side overlay
并且可以在客户端覆盖
that allowed you to leverage things like CDNs
利用CDN之类的东西
for, you know, optimize, streaming.
来优化流传输
As we have lost that and WebAssembly
由于我们已经告别了Flash 而WebAssembly
has not really replaced it in its ability,
从安全的角度来看
from a security perspective, to create a secure container.
并不能真正取代它来创建一个安全的容器
It has required a lot of server-side watermarking to occur,
因此这需要服务器端进行大量的水印处理
which then of course
毋庸置疑
creates more challenges with buffering. 164-p
这也会给缓冲带来更多的挑战 164-p
And VR 360, you know, just being able to play that back
而VR360 需要能够在数字版权保护下播放
with DRM, being able to maintain security as we move
当我们进一步踏入虚拟世界时
into more of these virtual worlds is going to be critical. 167-p
能够维护版权安全将是至关重要的 167-p
And then just for distribution, just offline tracking
然后是分发方面 离线追踪
tends to come up a lot, the security,
往往会遇到很多安全问题
when things go offline, how can we keep
在数据离线的情况下 我们要如何
some protection within the operating system or handoff
在操作系统中维持一些保护机制
between the browser and the operating system,
或保护浏览器和操作系统之间的交接
being able to download folders
能够下载文件夹
so that you can maintain those structures,
以便你可以保持这些结构
as we talked about the challenges on upload,
正如我们谈到的上传的挑战
and then just, you know, leveraging audio and AI analysis
然后大规模利用音频和人工智能分析
at scale, I think is going in the right direction
我认为正朝着正确的方向发展
and we'll be leveraging a lot more of that going forward. 178-p
我们将在未来更多利用它们 178-p
So I hope you found that useful,
希望你在这段演讲中有所收获
as some of the pipelines and tools used in the orchestration
比如我们在工作室协作中使用的
of a studio and some of the challenges we run into
流程和工具 以及我们遇到的挑战
and yeah, hopefully we can all work together
希望有朝一日我们能够并肩工作
to make it great.
共创辉煌